

Tran Minh Khoa

Site Reliability Engineer

Ho Chi Minh City, Viet Nam 0976940300 · khoatm2109@gmail.com

Date / Place of birth

09/21/1994, Saigon

Nationality

Vietnamese

Skills

Git

Linux

Kubernetes

Docker

CI/CD

Service Mesh Istio

GCP

AWS

C#

Terraform

Initiative and Problem-solving Abilities

JIRA

Confluence

Languages

English

Hobbies

Guitar Classic Motorbike RnB Singer Whiskey Lover Boxing Gym

Profile

Working as Site Reliability Engineer over 2 years. I'm a proactive. When I think about things, I do them. I like to see results and it's important in this role to be proactive and responsible for your own actions. Socially adept, offering a friendly and helpful attitude, and the ability to problem-solve well. A high-energy individual, with the ability to multitask and work well under pressure.

Employment History

Site Reliability Engineer, One Mount Group, Ho Chi Minh City

November 2019 - Present

- Config CI/CD process using Gitlab, always try organize Repository structure with highest convenient for develop team.
- Using Kaniko Cache to optimize build speed up to 30% with GCP Cloudbuild.
- Have knowledge about GCR, Kubernetes Engine, Dockerfile.
- Have knowledge about Kong API Gateway.
- Build infra to deploy Superset Data Visualization, using Python to custom Superset code for suitable with company business.
- Using Service Mesh Istio multi cluster for increase security, internal traffic, monitoring.
- Using Grafana, Prometheus, Kiali, Skywalking for monitoring all cluster in Mesh.
- Estimated cost, safety, and reliability during the design processes.
- Using K6 for service performance test, scability test to ensure System always High Availability.
- Using Splunk to manage service logs.
- Apply Velero to backup/migrate Kubernetes resources and persistent volumes.

DevOps Engineer, FPT Software, Ho Chi Minh City

August 2018 — October 2019

- Config Jenkins CI/CD process for all of project at FPT Software.
- Using Covertiy Scan, Sonar Scan, BlackDuck Scan to improve code of product.
- Code shellscript to deploy product to Cloud (Azure, AWS)
- Using some AWS services (VPC, S3, EC2, CodeDeploy, CodeCommit, Auto Scaling...) to standardize a project process in Cloud.

 Build full process CI/CD in AWS with Cloud team using CodePipeline and Blue/Green Deployment using ECR, ECS, CloudFormation, VPC, ELB for FPT Software AWS MSP Certificate.

System Administrator/Developer, FPT Software, Ho Chi Minh City

October 2016 — July 2018

Developer:

- Code shellscript Linux to import Oracle data in client side to Oracle Internal Server.
- Maintain and upgrade custom library of customer base on CakePHP (using PHP language)
- Join core team of C# project to get a system's business of customer and make a Detail Design for develop team
- Get Project Management Fundamental Certificate of FPT

System Administrator:

- Manage Virtual Machines for all of project in Business Unit 19
- Config Linux to deploy source PHP using Apache
- Setup private VLAN for Business Unit 19 with IT team
- Setup Foglight tool to use for measure Oracle SQL query performance

Quality Control Engineer, FPT Software, Ho Chi Minh City

April 2015 - September 2016

Automation Tester:

• Using Java Selenium Webdriver for automation test

QC Leader:

- Using Selenium IDE for training fresher.
- Lead 10 members, support Developer debug & fix bug.
- Implemented quality control standards.
- Provided quality control over documents as required.

Education

Bachelor, FPT Polytechnic College, Ho Chi Minh City

May 2012 - April 2015